♪I wrote a stroke♪
♪كتبتُ ضربةً♪
♪About you and me♪
♪عنك وعني♪
♪You pass like the wind♪
♪ تمرّين كالريح ♪
♪I follow like a leaf♪
أتبعها كالأوراق المتساقطة
♪But just you and me♪
♪لكن فقط أنت وأنا♪
♪Had no happy ending♪
♪لم تكن لها نهاية سعيدة♪
♪Perhaps it was just a chance encounter♪
♪ربما كان مجرد لقاء عابر♪
♪I turn memories over with great care♪
♪أُقلّب الذكريات بعناية فائقة♪
♪Afraid to lose the past♪
♪خائف من فقدان الماضي♪
♪Tears fall quietly with the plot♪
♪تتساقط الدموع بهدوء مع تطور الأحداث♪
♪Shattered with no response♪
♪محطمة بلا رد♪
♪The wind once♪
♪الريح ذات مرة♪
♪Through layers of mist♪
♪عبر طبقات من الضباب♪
♪And snowy scenes♪
♪ومشاهد ثلجية♪
♪Gently cradled the leaf in my palm♪
♪أمسكتُ بالورقة برفق في راحة يدي♪
♪But♪
♪لكن♪
♪Winds will cease♪
ستتوقف الرياح
♪Leaves will wither♪
♪ستذبل الأوراق♪
♪Our meeting was too fleeting♪
♪كان لقاؤنا خاطفاً جداً♪
♪It's an unavoidable fate♪
♪إنه مصير لا مفر منه♪
♪I too once♪
♪وأنا أيضاً ذات مرة♪
♪Walked through♪
♪مررنا عبر♪
♪A sea of people♪
♪بحر من الناس♪
♪Unafraid of how far it is♪
♪لا أخشى المسافة♪
♪Racing under stars toward you♪
♪أتسابق تحت النجوم نحوك♪
♪But♪
♪لكن♪
♪Time is heartless♪
♪الزمن قاسٍ بلا رحمة♪
♪You never yield♪
♪لن تستسلم أبداً♪
♪Let love remain♪
♪ليدم الحب♪
=Spring Night=
ليلة الربيع
=Episode 22=
=الحلقة 22=
Look out!
انتبه!
Go.
يذهب.
Go!
يذهب!
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
Please spare us!
أرجوكم ارحمونا!
Useless!
عديم الفائدة!
By order of the Prime Minister,
بأمر من رئيس الوزراء،
even the Crown Prince
حتى ولي العهد
must die.
يجب أن يموت.
His Majesty and the Crown Prince were assassinated.
تم اغتيال جلالته وولي العهد .
Prime Minister Qiu Xuanling
رئيس الوزراء تشيو شوانلينغ
arrived too late to save them.
وصلوا متأخرين جداً لإنقاذهم.
We only captured the assassin.
لقد قبضنا على القاتل فقط.
And this assassin
وهذا القاتل
is none other than the son of the criminal Shen Jinyuan,
إنه ليس سوى ابن المجرم شين جينيوان،
Shen Zhifeng.
شين زيفنغ.
To avenge his father,
للانتقام لأبيه،
Shen Zhifeng assassinated the Emperor.
اغتال شين تشيفنغ الإمبراطور.
His crime warrants death.
جريمته تستوجب الإعدام.
Tomorrow in court,
غداً في المحكمة،
Prime Minister Qiu Xuanling
رئيس الوزراء تشيو شوانلينغ
will execute him on the spot.
سوف أعدمه في الحال.
And the child
والطفل
in your womb
في رحمك
will be the sole royal heir.
سيكون الوريث الملكي الوحيد.
You will be
ستكون
the Empress Dowager,
الإمبراطورة الأرملة،
ruling from behind the curtain.
يحكمون من وراء الستار.
You're hesitating.
أنت متردد.
I'm one step away
أنا على بعد خطوة واحدة
from the imperial throne.
من العرش الإمبراطوري.
Why would I hesitate?
لماذا أتردد؟
An unborn child as royal heir
طفل لم يولد بعد كوريث ملكي
hasn't occurred
لم يحدث
since the Xiakang era.
منذ عهد شياكانغ.
My plan this time
خطتي هذه المرة
is quite inspired by antiquity, isn't it?
إنها مستوحاة بشكل كبير من العصور القديمة، أليس كذلك؟
At tomorrow's court session,
في جلسة المحكمة غداً،
this throne
هذا العرش
will change hands.
سيتم تغيير ملكيتها.
Everyone,
الجميع،
His Majesty and the Crown Prince
جلالة الملك وولي العهد
were assassinated
تم اغتيالهم
last night.
ليلة أمس.
Both have perished.
كلاهما هلك.
But fortunately,
لكن لحسن الحظ،
the assassin was captured alive on the spot.
تم القبض على القاتل حياً في مكان الحادث.
The child in the Crown Princess' womb
الطفل الذي في رحم ولية العهد
is the sole remaining royal heir.
هو الوريث الملكي الوحيد المتبقي.
The Crown Princess should act as regent
ينبغي أن تتولى ولية العهد دور الوصية على العرش
until the royal heir is born.
إلى حين ولادة الوريث الملكي.
Everyone,
الجميع،
any objections?
هل لديكم أي اعتراضات؟
I object!
أعترض!
A fetus on the throne?
جنين على العرش؟
Unheard of!
لم يسمع به!
You're acting
أنت تمثل
like a treacherous villain!
مثل شرير غادر!
His Majesty and the Crown Prince are dead.
لقد توفي جلالته وولي العهد.
The Crown Princess is my daughter.
ولية العهد هي ابنتي.
I am the royal father-in-law!
أنا والد الزوجة الملكي!
You.
أنت.
Who dares call me
من يجرؤ على الاتصال بي؟
a treacherous villain now?
أصبح الآن شريراً غادراً؟
Treacherous villain!
شرير غادر!
You!
أنت!
You're still alive?
هل ما زلت على قيد الحياة؟
You're utterly lawless.
أنت خارج عن القانون تماماً.
Qiu Xuanling.
تشيو شوانلينغ.
Look.
ينظر.
Know what this is?
هل تعرف ما هذا؟
Everyone,
الجميع،
this is
هذا هو
evidence collected years ago by Shen Jinyuan
الأدلة التي جمعها شين جينيوان قبل سنوات
of Qiu Xuanling's imperial exam fraud
تزوير تشيو شوانلينغ في الامتحانات الإمبراطورية
and corruption of the court!
وفساد المحكمة!
And you still deny being a treacherous villain?
وما زلت تنكر كونك شريراً غادراً؟
What a joke.
يا لها من مزحة!
The words of that criminal Shen Jinyuan
كلمات ذلك المجرم شين جينيوان
cannot be trusted.
لا يمكن الوثوق به.
The evidence is here.
الدليل موجود هنا.
What other excuses do you have?
ما هي الأعذار الأخرى التي لديك؟
I'll restore justice for the Shens.
سأعيد العدالة لعائلة شين.
Now, I ask you.
والآن، أسألكم.
Who truly
من هو حقاً
caused my father's death?
هل تسبب ذلك في وفاة والدي؟
Your father
والدك
was killed by this assassin,
قُتل على يد هذا القاتل،
Shen Zhifeng.
شين زيفنغ.
Shen Zhifeng is right here.
شين تشيفنغ موجود هنا.
Why execute him without trial?
لماذا أعدموه دون محاكمة؟
Do you intend to silence him
هل تنوي إسكاته؟
in front of everyone?
أمام الجميع؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I'm loyal.
أنا مخلص.
Why slander me so?
لماذا تشويه سمعتي هكذا؟
Could it be...
هل يمكن أن يكون...
that your delusional episode has recurred?
هل تكررت لديك نوبة الوهم ؟
Ridiculous!
سخيف!
Qiu Xuanling, I'm warning you!
تشيو شوانلينغ، أنا أحذرك!
I am still here.
ما زلت هنا.
She is
هي
unworthy of the throne.
غير جدير بالعرش.
Guards.
حراس.
His Highness' delusional episode has recurred.
لقد تكررت نوبة الهذيان التي أصابت صاحب السمو .
Escort His Highness to his palace.
رافقوا صاحب السمو إلى قصره.
Who dares?
من يجرؤ؟
Her child is not the royal heir.
طفلها ليس الوريث الملكي.
I am...
أنا أكون...
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
How dare a child of a disgraced minister spout nonsense here!
كيف يجرؤ ابن وزير مُدان على التفوّه بهذا الهراء هنا!
I shall execute you this instant!
سأعدمك في هذه اللحظة!
Kill me.
اقتلني.
Then you cannot kill him.
إذن لا يمكنك قتله.
Have you forgotten
هل نسيت؟
what I have taught you
ما علمته لك
through the years?
على مر السنين؟
You fool!
يا أحمق!
♪The wind drifts alone and free♪
♪الريح تنجرف وحيدة وحرة♪
♪Through seasons, none asks of me♪
♪على مرّ الفصول، لا أحد يطلب مني♪
♪Spring fades, and autumn wails♪
♪يتلاشى الربيع، ويبكي الخريف♪
♪Only the waning moon lights my solitude♪
♪لا ينير عزلتي إلا ضوء القمر المتضائل ♪
♪Love arose with the wind's sigh♪
♪نشأ الحب مع زفرة الريح♪
♪On a cold night, a swan's shadow flashes by♪
♪في ليلة باردة، يمر ظل بجعة سريعًا♪
♪You're deeply devoted♪
♪أنت شديد الإخلاص♪
♪Yet spring wind betrayed your heart♪
لكن رياح الربيع خانت قلبك.
♪I miss you so much♪
♪أفتقدك كثيراً♪
♪I never forget you♪
♪لن أنساك أبداً♪
♪A brief period of love-sickness♪
♪ فترة قصيرة من ألم الحب ♪
♪You won my heart over♪
لقد فزتَ بقلبي!
♪Why did we first meet♪
♪لماذا التقينا لأول مرة؟♪
♪Seeking spring's song and night whispers♪
♪أبحث عن أغنية الربيع وهمسات الليل♪
♪Long autumn comes, and wild geese southward fly♪
♪يأتي الخريف الطويل، وتهاجر الأوز البرية جنوباً♪
♪The azure clouds know my name♪
♪السحب الزرقاء تعرف اسمي♪
♪I remember you, and you understand me♪
أتذكرك، وأنت تفهمني
♪Watching the sun set♪
♪مشاهدة غروب الشمس♪
♪Autumn departs, and beauty fades away♪
يرحل الخريف، ويتلاشى الجمال.
♪To lean on you once more someday♪
♪لأعتمد عليك مرة أخرى يوماً ما♪